[{"question":"In which year did WWII start?", "answersList":[1914, 1918, 1939, 1945], "answer":"1939"},
{"question":"In which country was Adolf Hitler born?", "answersList":["Germany", "Austria", "Switzerland", "France"], "answer":"Austria"},
{"question":"Who was the first president of America?", "answersList":["Thomas Jefferson", "John Adams", "George Washington", "Abraham Lincoln"], "answer":"George Washington"},
{"question":"In which year was American president John F. Kennedy assassinated?", "answersList":[1963, 1964, 1965, 1969], "answer":"1963"},
{"question":"How many wives did King Henry VIII have?", "answersList":[1, 4, 8, 6], "answer":6},
{"question":"What was the code name for the Nazi invasion of Russia in 1941?", "answersList":["Operation Ursula", "Operation Otto", "Operation Barbarossa", "Operation Bernhard"], "answer":"Operation Barbarossa"},
{"question":"In which year did Tony Blair become the prime minister?", "answersList":[1993, 1997, 2001, 2005], "answer":1997},
{"question":"In which year did William the Conquerer defeat King Harold at the battle of Hastings?", "answersList":[1022, 1044, 1088, 1066], "answer":1066},
{"question":"In which year was the Great Fire of London?", "answersList":[1666, 1665, 1602, 1702], "answer":1666},
{"question":"In which year was the Gunpowder plot thwarted?", "answersList":[1600, 1605, 1610, 1615], "answer":1605},
{"question":"In which year was the Battle of Waterloo?", "answersList":[1815, 1715, 1865, 1915], "answer":1815},
{"question":"In which year did Queen Victoria become the British monarch?", "answersList":[1817, 1827, 1837, 1847], "answer":1837},
{"question":"In which month did the Allies accept Germnay's surrender in 1945?", "answersList":["February", "March", "April", "May"], "answer":"May"},
{"question":"In which year did Christopher Columbus discover America?", "answersList":[1472, 1482, 1492, 1502], "answer":1492},
{"question":"In which year did America declare independence from Britain?", "answersList":[1776, 1765, 1715, 1795], "answer":1776},
{"question":"In which year did the American Civil War break out?", "answersList":[1821, 1841, 1881, 1861], "answer":1861},
{"question":"In which year did the USSR launch the first Satellite, Sputnik 1?", "answersList":[1945, 1957, 1954, 1961], "answer":1957},
{"question":"In which year did Yuri Gagarin become the first man to enter space?", "answersList":[1959, 1961, 1963, 1964], "answer":1961},
{"question":"In which year did former British Prime Minister Sir Winston Churchill die?", "answersList":[1959, 1962, 1965, 1968], "answer":1965},
{"question":"In which year did Roald Amundsen and his crew become the first men to reach the South Pole?", "answersList":[1881, 1901, 1911, 1921], "answer":"1911"},
{"question":"In which year did Alan Shepard become the first American to enter space?", "answersList":[1961, 1963, 1965, 1967], "answer":1961},
{"question":"In which year was Nicholas II crowned Czar of Russia?", "answersList":[1886, 1896, 1906, 1916], "answer":1896},
{"question":"In which year was the Treaty of Versailles signed bringing an end to the First World War between Germany and most of the Allied nations?", "answersList":[1917, 1918, 1921, 1919], "answer":1919},
{"question":"In which year did American President Dwight D. Eisenhower sign the legislation ordering the creation of NASA?", "answersList":[1949, 1952, 1955, 1958], "answer":1958},
{"question":"In which year did Greece host the first international olympic games in modern history?", "answersList":[1896, 1872, 1888, 1892], "answer":1896}]
